A Guide to the Rockefeller family papers, Sound and Video Recordings FA1787
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller family papers, Sound and Video Recordings
1964-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
Rockefeller, Margaretta Fitler
FA1787
4.84 Cubic Feet 9 letter document boxes (containing 61 U-matic videotapes).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Audio and video recordings.
- Video Recordings, 1964-1982; 1; 4.84 Cubic Feet 9 letter document boxes (containing 61 U-matic videotapes).
  Moving Images
  - Greenaway - A Documentary by Sue Gilbert, circa 1970s; Sound, Color, 51 minutes; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 12044)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research. Digital access copy available.
    Scope and Contents
    Abrakadabra Productions, Inc.
  - Nelson Rockefeller - Memorial Service, Riverside Church - Conclusion of Funeral from ABC-TV Broadcast, 1979 February 2; U-matic; Sound, Color, 11 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 12045)
    Original tape annotation:"Recorded at RAC" - Production B. Tape contains TV broadcast conclusion of Nelson A. Rockefeller's funeral, includes commentators remarks.
  - Nelson Rockefeller - Memorial Service, Riverside Church - Outside Riverside Church and Arrivals, 1979 February 2; U-matic; Sound, Color, 33 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 12046)
    Original tape annotation: "Only in front of church." Tape contains exterior footage from in front of Riverside Church as funeral attendees arrive. Footage of Happy Rockefeller and children.
  - Nelson Rockefeller - Memorial Service, Riverside Church - Beginning of Funeral, 1979 February 2; U-matic; Sound, Color (Box 1, Tape AV 12047)
    Original tape annotation: "Unedited tape" - Tape supplied by ABC Television. Contains exterior footage of attendees arriving at Riverside Church, exterior shots of the church, President Jimmy Carter and First Lady Rosalind Carter, choir entrance, and the first part of the funeral service: Speakers include David Rockefeller and Henry Kissinger.
  - Nelson Rockefeller - Memorial Service, Riverside Church - Conclusion of Funeral., 1979 February 2; U-matic; Sound, Color, 46 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 12048)
    Original tape annotation: "Unedited FILM" - Tape supplied by ABC Television. Tape contains conclusion of funeral, including conclusion of Henry Kissinger's remarks, exiting of the guests to the tune "Sweet Georgia Brown," and exterior sidewalk shots of guests leaving funeral.
  - David Rockefeller - Interviewed by Bill Moyers - Tape 1, 1980 February 7; U-matic; Sound, Color, 48 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 12049)
    9:00 PM
    Related Materials
    Also see: David Rockefeller Personal and Professional papers, RG 1 and RG 2, FA436
  - David Rockefeller - Interviewed by Bill Moyers - Tape 2, 1980 February 7; U-matic; Sound, Color, 32 minutes (Box 2, Tape AV 12050)
  - The Urban Challenge: Rockefeller's New York Legacy, 1975 August 26; U-matic; Sound, Color, 29 minutes (Box 2, Tape AV 12051)
    TV program discussing Nelson A. Rockefeller. Host: Robert Abrams, Bronx Boro President. Guests: Mary Nichols, Senior Editor of The Village Voice, and Myer Kutz, author of "Rockefeller Power."
  - Nelson Rockefeller on "Meet the Press", 1975 June 15; U-matic; Sound, Color, 26 minutes (Box 2, Tape AV 12052)
    New program discussing the commission to investigate Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) activity within the United States.
    Also see: Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential records, Video Recordings, Series 20, FA798
  - Gerald Ford at Committee Hearing on Nixon Pardon- Tape 1, 1974 October 17; Sound, Color, 62 minutes; U-matic (Box 2, Tape AV 12053)
  - Gerald Ford at Committee Hearing on Nixon Pardon- Tape 2, 1974 October 17; Sound, Color, 61 minutes; U-matic (Box 2, Tape AV 12054)
  - Places in the News: Rockefeller the Number 2 Man, 1975 January 16; U-matic; Sound, Black and white, 20 minutes (Box 2, Tape AV 12055)
    WNYE Channel 2: Profile of Nelson A. Rockefeller on the occasion of his vice presidency. Includes family newsreel and television footage.
  - Georgians Speak: Dr. Martin Luther King Sr., 1975 January 10; Sound, Color, 29 minutes; U-matic; Dale Clark, Director of Public Affairs, and Emmanuel Hall, Director of Community Affairs, interview Dr. Martin Luther King Senior at the time of his retirement. WAGA Productions. (Box 2, Tape AV 12056)
  - Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller 3rd on "Sunday" (NBC-TV), 1975 January 19; U-matic; Sound, Color, 17 minutes (Box 3, Tape AV 12057)
    Discussion with John D. Rockefeller 3rd and his wife Blanchette Ferry Hooker Rockefeller on their Asian art collection.
  - Admiral's House - Happy Rockefeller, 1975 September 7; U-matic; Sound, Color, 3 minutes (Box 3, Tape AV 12058)
    ABC-TV News: Report on Nelson and Happy Rockefeller's home during his Vice Presidency.
  - Dorothy Fuldheim Interview with Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1974 June 17; U-matic; Sound, Color, 13 minutes (Box 3, Tape AV 12059)
    WEWS TV 5 - Cleveland, Ohio. Original tape annotation: "Lively NAR Interview"
    General
    Nelson Rockefeller interview duration is 13 minutes. The remainder of the tape contains various TV programs and commercials.
  - Brief News Report at a "Youth for Reagan" Rally, circa 1976; U-matic; Sound, Color, 1 minute (Box 3, Tape AV 12060)
    circa 1976
  - Bicentennial: Beyond the Birthday, 1975 February 17; U-matic; Sound, Color, 39 minutes (Box 3, Tape AV 12061)
    Program about proposed Bicentennial declaration and events. President Gerald Ford.
  - "Today Show": Rockefeller Segment - Part 2 (NBC-TV), 1976 August 18; Sound, Color; U-matic (Box 3, Tape AV 12062)
  - I Used to Have Cancer (ABC-TV) - Happy Rockefeller, 1977 January 5; Sound, Color; U-matic (Box 3, Tape AV 12063)
  - Dallas News Conference (WFAA, KXAS, KERA and KDFW), 1975 September 12; Sound, Color; U-matic (Box 4, Tape AV 12064)
  - John D. Rockefeller IV Interview on the "Today Show" (NBC-TV), 1977; Sound, Color, 11 minutes; U-matic (Box 4, Tape AV 12065)
    Report on Inauguration of John D "Jay" Rockefeller IV as Governor of West Virginia. Contains footage of Sharon Percy Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller IV, and family. Reporter: Tom Brockaw.
  - Inauguration of John D. Rockefeller IV - West Virginia Inaugural, 1977 January 17; U-matic; Sound, Color, 36 minutes (Box 4, Tape AV 12066)
    Inauguration ceremonies program. Broadcast on television. Announcer: Tom Berger
  - "Inside Iowa" - Interview with Vice-President Nelson A. Rockefeller (WHO-TV), 1976 April 15; U-matic; Sound, Color, 30 minutes (Box 4, Tape AV 12067)
    Election year discussion. Interviewers: Bob Willbanks, Jack Thompson
  - MacNeil/Lehrer Special Edition: "Carter Energy Plan" - John D. Rockefeller IV appearance - Part 1, 1977 April 20; U-matic; Sound, Color, 62 minutes (Box 4, Tape AV 12068)
    News discussion around President Jimmy Carter's attempt at a comprehensive national energy program. Also appearing: Michael Dukakis, Governor of Massachusetts; Richard Lamb, Governor of Colorado; Edwin Edwards, Governor of Louisiana; James Thompson, Governor of Illinois; Jay Rockefeller, Governor of West Virginia. WNET Channel 13
  - MacNeil/Lehrer Special Edition: "Carter Energy Plan" - John D. Rockefeller IV appears - Part 2, 1977 April 20; Sound, Color, 26 minutes; U-matic (Box 4, Tape AV 12069)
    Conclusion of news discussion around President Jimmy Carter's attempt at a comprehensive national energy program. Also appearing: Michael Dukakis, Governor of Massachusetts; Richard Lamb, Governor of Colorado; Edwin Edwards, Governor of Louisiana; James Thompson, Governor of Illinois; Jay Rockefeller, Governor of West Virginia. WNET Channel 13
  - "Good Morning America": Vice President Nelson A. Rockefeller Interview, 1976; U-matic; Sound, Color, 7 minutes (Box 5, Tape AV 12070)
    Interview from Republican National Convention. ABC-TV
  - Juan Carlos I, King of Spain, undated; Sound, Color, 22 minutes; U-matic (Box 5, Tape AV 12071)
    Juan Carlos I: Rey de España. No do Presenta: Revista cinematografica Español, Edicion Especial. United States Navy, Naval Air Systems Command
  - State University of New York (SUNY) Plaza Dedication - Edited Version, 1978 June 5; Sound, Color, 51 minutes; U-matic (Box 5, Tape AV 12072)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller in attendance.
  - John D Rockefeller - Teltone News (WABC-TV), 1981 March 6; Sound, Color, 4 minutes; U-matic (Box 5, Tape AV 12073)
    Short profile of John D. Rockefeller titled "The First J.R." Contains newsreel footage. Aired: Friday at 7:30pm
  - Vice President Nelson Rockefeller - Paulskirche (St. Paul's Church) - Frankfurt, Germany - Part 1, 1976 May 15; U-matic; Sound, Black and white, 57 minutes (Box 5, Tape AV 12074)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Poor image quality throughout.
    Includes Nelson Rockefeller speech. Tape mostly in German.
  - Vice President Nelson Rockefeller - Paulskirche (St. Paul's Church) - Frankfurt, Germany - Part 2, 1976 May 15; U-matic; Sound, Color, 50 minutes (Box 5, Tape AV 12075)
    Continuation of tape AV 12074.
    Poor image quality throughout
  - David Frost Show: Governor Nelson A Rockefeller Interviewed - Part 1 (WNEW/TV, Channel 5, New York), 1971 August 5; Sound, Color, 62 minutes; U-matic (Box 5, Tape AV 12076)
    Television interview. Includes 60 second program promotional clip.
  - David Frost Show: Governor Nelson A Rockefeller Interviewed - Part 2 (WNEW/TV, Channel 5, New York), 1971 August 5; Sound, Color, 28 minutes; U-matic (Box 6, Tape AV 12077)
    Continuation of television interview.
  - John D. Rockefeller III Death Announcement - 10 O'Clock News - WNEW/TV - Channel 5 New York, 1978 July 13; Sound, Color, 4 minutes; U-matic (Box 6, Tape AV 12078)
    Contains funeral footage and audio of eulogy by John D Rockefeller IV. Aired: 10:00 PM
  - John D Rockefeller III Funeral Services - 6 O'Clock News - WCBS/TV - Channel 2 New York, 1978 July 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; U-matic (Box 6, Tape AV 12079)
    Report of the funeral, contains footage. Aired: 06:00 PM
  - John D Rockefeller III Funeral Services - Action News - WPIX/TV - Channel 11 New York - 7:30pm, 1978 July 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; U-matic (Box 6, Tape AV 12080)
    Report on John D Rockefeller III funeral. Includes footage from outside Riverside Church. Aired: 07:30 PM
  - Rocky's Place, circa 1975; U-matic; Sound, Color, 2 minutes (Box 6, Tape AV 12081)
    Report on opening of the Admirel's House for Vice President Nelson Rockefeller. Happy Rockefeller takes guests on a tour of the resident. Report by Dan Rather.
  - Gran Gala en Nueva York - Instituto Español (Spanish Institute) - 1981 Gold Medal - Gala TV Show, Sound, Color, 50 minutes; U-matic (Box 6, Tape AV 12082)
    Raymundo De Larrain presenta. Participants: Margaret Rockefeller De Larrain, Placido Domingo. International Production Center (IPC)
  - Th Rockefeller Park, a Spaulding/Sladkus Production, 1982; U-matic; Sound, Color, 17 minutes (Box 6, Tape AV 12083)
    Interviews by Emilie Spaudling. Edited by Dan Sladkus. Program about the creation of Rockefeller State Park Preserve. Bob Snyder, President - Greenrock Inc, is interviewed. Includes archival photographs of Rockefeller family. McLean Cable Associates
    Slight audio buzz throughout.
  - Bicentennial Town Meeting - Vice President Nelson A Rockefeller interview, 1976 September 25; Sound, Color, 12 minutes; U-matic (Box 7, Tape AV 12084)
    Mount Pleasant Council presents: Bicentennial Town Meeting "to write a community master plan." Location: New Sardis Baptist Church, 9:00AM to 4:00PM. Vice President Nelson Rockefeller interviewed. Contains TV commercials.
  - Nelson A Rockefeller - Memorial Service - Riverside Church - Part 1, 1979 February 2; U-matic; Sound, Color, 63 minutes (Box 7, Tape AV 12085)
    Televised news broadcast of Nelson Rockefeller's memorial. WNBC-TV
  - Nelson A Rockefeller - Memorial Service - Riverside Church - Part 2, 1979 February 2; Sound, Color, 62 minutes; U-matic (Box 7, Tape AV 12086)
    Continuation of televised news broadcast of Nelson Rockefeller's memorial. WNBC-TV
  - Nelson A Rockefeller - Memorial Service - Riverside Church - Part 3, 1979 February 2; Sound, Color, 15 minutes; U-matic (Box 7, Tape AV 12087)
    Conclusion of televised news broadcast of Nelson Rockefeller's memorial. WNBC-TV
  - Nelson A Rockefeller Memorial - WNET/TV 13 - Tape 1 of 2, 1979 February; Sound, Color, 60 minutes; U-matic (Box 7, Tape AV 12088)
    "Live" television coverage of Nelson Rockefeller's memorial at Riverside Church, New York City. WNET Channel 13 (Newark, New Jersey)
  - Nelson A Rockefeller Memorial - WNET/TV 13 - Tape 2 of 2, 1979 February; Sound, Color, 24 minutes; U-matic (Box 7, Tape AV 12089)
    Continuation of "live" television coverage of Nelson Rockefeller's memorial at Riverside Church, New York City. WNET Channel 13 (Newark, New Jersey
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Memorial Service, 1979 February; Sound, Color, 62 minutes; U-matic (Box 8, Tape AV 12096)
    "Live" television coverage of Nelson A Rockefeller's memorial at Riverside Church. Pia Lindstrom reporting.
  - Family Funeral Services for Nelson A Rockefeller (TV news compilation), 1979; U-matic; Sound, Color, 19 minutes (Box 8, Tape AV 12091)
    Compilation of television reports on Nelson Rockefeller's funeral and circumstances around his death. Includes footage outside Kykuit and images of grave.
  - Midday 'Live' - Nelson A. Rockefeller book: "I Never Wanted to be Vice President of Anything", circa 1976; U-matic; Sound, Color, 30 minutes (Box 7, Tape AV 12090)
    Television interview program discussing the book "I Never Wanted to be Vice President of Anything: An Investigative Biography of Nelson A. Rockefeller." Guests: Michael Kramer, contributing editor of New York Magazine; Sam Roberts, Chief Political Correspondent of New York Daily News
  - Attica - ABC-TV Dramatization - Part 1, c. 1980; Sound, Color, 54 minutes; U-matic (Box 8, Tape AV 12092)
    Made-for-TV movie. ABC Sunday Night Movie
  - Attica - ABC-TV Dramatization - Part 2, c. 1980; Sound, Color, 52 minutes; U-matic (Box 8, Tape AV 12093)
    Conclusion of made-for-TV movie. ABC Sunday Night Movie
  - "And the Wilderness Shall Bloom" - The Henry Morrison Flagler Museum, 1981; U-matic; Sound, Color, 28 minutes (Box 8, Tape AV 12095)
    The story of Henry Morrison Flagler and the east coast of Florida. Written, produced, and directed by Aaron M. Cohen.
  - "Face to Face" - John D. Rockefeller Jr, 1976 January 10; Sound, Color, 31 minutes; U-matic (Box 8, Tape AV 12097)
    Television news program examining the state of the arts in eduacation. Program for Arts Education Anniversary. Features David Rockefeller Jr.
  - Nelson A Rockefeller - Swearing In as Vice President, 1974 December 19; U-matic; Sound, Color, 30 minutes (Box 9, Tape AV 12098)
    "Live" television coverage of Nelson A Rockefeller taking his oath of office in the Chamber of the United States Senate.
  - "Issues and Answers" - Vice President Nelson Rockefeller - ABC-TV, 1975 November 2; U-matic; Sound, Color, 29 minutes (Box 9, Tape AV 12099)
    Interview with Vice President Nelson A Rockefeller. Topics include: New York City bankrupcy and whether Rockefeller will remain the Vice Presidential nominee in 1976.
  - Dedication of the Nelson A. Rockefeller Institute of Government (State University of New York/SUNY), 1982 October 6; U-matic; Sound, Color, 30 minutes (Box 9, Tape AV 12100)
    In attendance: Hugh Carey, Governor of New York; Happy Rockefeller; David Rockefeller. "SUNY Historic Moments" Series
  - SUNY 25th Anniversary Ceremonies in the New York State Legislature, 1973 March 13; U-matic; Sound, Color, 51 minutes (Box 9, Tape AV 12102)
    State University of New York (SUNY). Presentation of Distinguished Service Medallions. Seven awards given including Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Videotaped highlights.
  - "AM New York" - Steven Rockefeller Jr. Interview, 1982; Sound, Color, 27 minutes; U-matic (Box 9, Tape AV 12103)
    Television interview with Steven Rockefeller Jr. regarding his grandfather Nelson Rockefeller, on being a member of the Rockefeller family, about his interests, and his mother's artwork.
  - In Celebration of US: Our Happiest Birthday - CBS-TV, 1976 July 4; U-matic; Sound, Color, 51 minutes (Box 9, Tape AV 12104)
    United States Bicentennial program narrated by Walter Cronkite.